# Spencer Dye

sdye9699@gmail.com • (509) 881-4113 • Portfolio • GitHub • LinkedIn

### Summary

Front-End Developer with 2.5+ years professional experience. Background in design, transitioned to development. Experience designing and developing responsive, interactive web experiences using technologies like React, TypeScript, and Headless CMSs. Skilful in contributing to a collaborative work environment, solving problems and creative thinking.

#### Skills

Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, TypeScript, SASS,

Frameworks & CMSs: React, Tailwindcss, Strapi, Magento, WordPress, Webflow CMS

Tools/Utilities: Rest APIs, Git, Vercel, Webflow, Shopify Methodologies/Other Skills: BEM, UX/UI Design Software: VS Code, Figma, Illustrator, Photoshop

#### Relevant Experience

# **Spire Marketing** *Pensacola, FL* (*Remote*)

July 2021 - Jul 2022

Web Developer

- Developed from finalized designs turning them into fully interactive and responsive sites. Made structural decisions on client sites that led to a cumulative 130% visitor increase in a 3-month span.
- Developed modern UIs using UI libraries like MUI and Ant Design to create custom components.
- Worked in a team environment maintaining clear, consistent communication to keep the projects on track. Provided daily updates to keep team members informed on project developments. Maintained project timelines to keep them on time. Was able to save an average of 20% on allocated hours.
- Created multiple CMS libraries for things like blogs, service pages, and cross referenced libraires to allow other members of the team to add content to client sites which resulted in costs savings.
- Made layout decisions in order to ensure a clear user-flow which resulted in a 45% sales increase on a client site. Developed and maintained additional pages that were added over time.

## Independent Freelance (Remote)

January 2020 – Present

Web Designer & Developer

- Developed client sites using technologies like React and Strapi for the headless CMS. Wrote logic for pop-ups and other prompts on many client sites that resulted in increased conversions.
- Developed responsive, dynamic websites in Webflow using features like CMS, flexbox, grid, interactions, animations. Wrote JavaScript, HTML, and CSS to take the site capabilities above what is natively available in Webflow.
- Performed SEO on sites (meta data, analytics tagging, schema markup, and semantic structure).
- Developed websites for two separate agencies while maintaining freedom with structural decisions.
- Met with clients to develop a vision for the design. Created wireframes and high-fidelity mock-ups in programs like Figma. Presented designs to clients for feedback and made alterations when needed.

### **Education**

### Wenatchee Valley College, Wenatchee, WA

June 2018

Associates of Arts & Science

Graceland University, Lamoni, IA Completed 90 credits toward BA in Computer Science August 2019 - May 2021